<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Sandeep Namburi</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-12-01T00:51:26+00:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Sandeep Namburi</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>sandeep.namburi.31@gmail.com</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[GapMinder Analysis]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/gapminder-analysis/" />
  <id>/gapminder-analysis</id>
  <updated>2015-11-30T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2015-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Sandeep Namburi</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>sandeep.namburi.31@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#overview&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#approach&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-approach&quot;&gt;Approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis is part of the Wesleyan University’s Data Analysis course. Thanks Lisa Dierker for putting through the course.
I have selected gapminder dataset for the analysis. I am interested to see how Suicide (per 100,000 people) correlates with inflation (annual %). I believe there will be a direct correlation between the two -as the inflation rises, suicides go up. Both of these variables are not part of the cookbook. I have decided to download the datasets from the Gapminder website myself. Also, unfortunately, there is no consolidated dataset having all the variables at one place. I am going to, as a part of my analysis, download all the 519 variables and consolidate the information.  I have already begun parsing all the data spreadsheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;approach&quot;&gt;Approach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make available the gapminder dataset with all 519 variables. I beleive this will help others have all the data at place and help correlate various variables at once. Here is my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/snamburi3/gapminder&quot;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt; for this project. I am presently doing the data ETL work - mainly cleaning and transforming the dataset into tidy format. I have not developed a full research question yet. Once I have all the varirables, I want to see if I can develop a question from the dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/gapminder-analysis/&quot;&gt;GapMinder Analysis&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Sandeep Namburi at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Sandeep Namburi&lt;/a&gt; on November 30, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
